Lock Jia Yi

Early Childhood Educator; English Preschool Teacher

8671 3684

iayilock205@gmail.com

BLK147 Toa Payoh Lor 2 310147 #40-336 Singapore

20 May 1998

Zoom: jiayilock205@gmail.com

SKILLS

9/10

Child-centred Approach & Enquiry learning

9/10

Time & Stress Management

8.5/10

Communication & Interpersonal Skill

8/10

Project planning & Problem solving

10/10

Teamwork & Commitment

EDUCATION & OUALIFICATION

Diploma in Early Childhood Studies with Merit

TEMASEK POLYTECHNIC

2016-2019

- * cGPA 3.7
- * School of Humanities and Social Science (HSS) Director's List for 2 consecutive years (AY2016-2018)
- * Cengage Learning Asia Prize Recipient (2019)
- * Co-curricular Activity (CCA) Merit Award- Leadership (2017)

SPM (equivalent to GCE O-Level)

SMK CANOSSIAN CONVENT KLUANG JOHOR

2011-2015

* 10 A's result

ABOUT ME

A L2 ECDA-certified and first-aid certified preschool teacher with 2 years of experience teaching preschoolers aged 2-6 years old in classroom setting of up to 17 younger learners (with assistant teacher support).

An enthusiastic preschool educator who is dedicated to providing engaging and quality learning experience. Strive to optimize children's involvement and interest to explore fearlessly. Recognised for cheerfulness and ability to build up young learners' pro-social behaviours and self-confidence through recognition, reinforcement and positive quidance.

EXPERIENCE

Preschool Teacher, English

MindChamps Preschool @TPY (August 2019-Present)

Full-time English preschool teacher who experienced 200 hours staff training as well as taking charge of manpower arrangement and planning weekly roster.

- Plan, prepare and implement child-directed lessons and Enquiry-based learning activities in accordance with termly themes, developmental milestones and centre's philosophy pedagogy
- Develop experiential and hands-on learning experiences in small group settings. For example, taste tests, sensorial experiments, gourmet moments etc.
- Design quality and conducive classroom environment based on different themes or events that prioritize children's safety and hygiene
- Cater the emotional, social, cognitive and physical needs of each child
- Administer medication and basic first aid to unwell or injured children
- Be responsible for all aspects of classroom management
- Facilitate children during enrichment programmes, such as Music classes, movement activities at gym, Reading & Writing programme etc.
- Conduct observation and documentation of child's growth portfolio twice a term as well as progress report for each semester
- Maintain a close partnership with parents through daily communication both face-to-face and via an authorized 24/7 apps, weekly updates and etc.
- Exchange and share ideas across the learning & teaching process, progress delivery and achieved learning outcomes with colleagues and leaders by the end of each term



LOCK JIA YI

(+65) 8671 3684

jiayilock205@gmail.com

BLK 147 TOA PAYOH LOR 2 #40-336 310147

COMPUTER LITERACY SKILLS

- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel & PowerPoint)
- Video-editing
- Remote teaching (Zoom & MS TEAMS)
- Event invitation card & Posters

L A N G U A G E P R O F I C I E N C Y



REFEREES

MS JENNY CHEOK

Care Person, Lecturer, Temasek Polytechnic 6780 6482 (Office) 9846 1131 (HP) Jenny_cheok@niec.edu.sg

MS BOEY SUIT YIM

Mentor, Advisor of International Student Group, Temasek Polytechnic 6780 6010 (Office) 9756 6842 (HP) suityim@tp.du.sq

EXPERIENCE

Relief Preschool teacher, English

MindChamps Preschool@TPY (February 2019- May 2019)

Relief English preschool teacher who was under the mentorship of a Senior teacher and co-teaching in Nursery levels up to K2 graduation batch.

- Helped managing classrooms of up to 20 children ranging from 2-6 years old (Playgroup – K2 classes)
- Fostered and maintained a fun, warm and nurturing atmosphere conducive to learning and creative expression
- Guided children with different learning styles and attended to those who required additional attention and explanation (No child left behind)
- Discussed, drafted and developed lesson plans and enquiry projects with the class teachers and senior teacher
- Planned and drafted a consent form and letter prior to the field trips
- Assisted class teachers during in-class and outdoor activities
- Conducted relief teaching during term break or teachers who were on leave
- Design and establish teacher-made zone materials that further enhanced children's numeracy skills and motor coordination.

Intern Preschool teacher, English

My First Skool@Tampines 4 (September 2018- March 2019)

An Intern who was under the mentorship of experienced class teachers and applied both theoretical and practical knowledges during 6-months, full-time practicum.

- Conducted classroom observation and research on how children learn and comprehend sciences and the effectiveness of engaging learning tools
- Conducted daily assembly in the morning and gathering session
- Proposed and established daily read-aloud session to instil the love of reading and literacy competence among young learners
- Disinfected toys and learning materials each day based on the hygiene and cleanliness guidelines
- Kept and maintained a clean and safe classroom by promoting good hygiene habits with children

LEADERSHIP

MindChamps Preschool@TPY

- Take charge of centre manpower arrangement and Weekly Rosters
- Centre's Annual Events organiser and planner
- Term break & Holiday programme coordinator
- Presenter of Annual Curriculum Talk
- Guide & support newly-joined teachers

2011-2019

- Class representative in Temasek Polytechnic
- Honorary Treasurer of student club

- Organiser of CCA events
- Integration Ambassador of Temasek Polytechnic
- Class monitor in Secondary school
- School prefect for 3 consecutive years
- Assistant commander of House Marching Band

CERTIFICATION 8 ACHIEVEMENTS

2019-Present

- Certified Child First Aid (BCLS+ AED) valid till August 2022
- Tip Toe Awards (From AY 2020 Term 1-4)
- ECDA CPD Course- Progress Tracking in Numeracy Development (14 hours)

2011-2018

- Cengage Learning Asia Prize
- School of Humanities and Social Science (HSS) Director's List (AY2017/2018)
- School of Humanities and Social Science (HSS) Director's List (AY2016/2017)
- Co-curriculum Activity (CCA) Merit Award (leadership)
- Malaysia National Chemistry Quiz (Merit)

SPECIAL INTEREST

- Highly value outdoor and movement activities that emphasize on both fine and gross motor skills (eg. playing badminton, Track & Field, cycling
- Enjoy integrating music and song in teaching and learning process
- Conduct cooking class and gourmet moment for the little ones to practice self-help skills; boost their confidence; build on their numeracy concept and language skills

EXPECTED SALARY

\$3400-\$3500

LOCK JIA YI

(+65) 8671 3684

jiayilock205@gmail.com

BLK 147 TOA PAYOH LOR 2 #40-336 310147

March 30, 2021

Ministry of Education

Customer Service Centre

1 North Buona Vista Drive

MOE Building, Podium Block

Singapore 138675

Dear Sir/ Madam,

I was pleased to learn of your need for a Preschool L2 English teacher. I am an ambitious preschool educator who strive for continuous improvement and opportunities of growth at work. MOE Kindergarten is well-known for providing authentic and holistic education to every child and partnering families from all walks of life. With a promise of "Leaving No One Behind", your kindergarten has a reputation as one of Singapore's most recommended early childhood organization. Aligned with personal teaching-learning philosophy, I am confident to be a part of the team players within your organization.

The following are highlights of my background, skills and accomplishment:

- Presently serving at MindChamps Preschool as a L2- English teacher for nearly 2 years and holding a valid first-aid certificate
- Noted for my patience and capacity for guiding Chinese to English/ bilingual speakers as well as instilling confidence and resilience
- Planning and taking charge of weekly manpower arrangement for centre staffs
- Proactively communicate with parents to acknowledge their child's accomplishment and
 parental support as well as addressing areas of concern through discussions, phone call,
 messages via an authorized app, newsletter, weekly updates and etc.
- Previously shortlisted and was employed as an intern at My First Skool@Tampines 4 for 6 months during the final year in Temasek Polytechnic
- Graduated with a Diploma in Early Childhood Studies with Merit (with a cumulative GPA (cGPA) of 3.7)

Beyond my teaching experiences, I am prepared to take CPD courses and constantly improve my career prospects. Having a lifelong passion in EC education, I believe my qualification, combined with abilities and experiences in early childhood sector would make me an ideal candidate for this role.

Attached is my resume for further references. I am excited at the prospect of bringing my talents to MOE Kindergarten, hence, do feel free to contact me for additional information or clarification if needed.

I look forward to hearing from you, at your earliest convenience to further discuss the job opportunity ad how my qualification, experience and skills will best serve the teaching role offered.

Thank you for your time and consideration

Sincerely,

Jia Yi